<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns= "http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<id>urn:uuid:97c7907f-1503-48ce-b37f-6cbfeff1d042</id>
<link rel="self" href="https://productivityintech.com/files/feed.xml" />
<author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
<updated>2017-08-27T02:53:41Z</updated>
<title>Productivity in Tech Blog</title>
<subtitle>Posts from the Productivity in Tech Blog.</subtitle>
<icon>files/images/feed_icon.png</icon>
<logo>files/image/feed_logo.png</logo>
<generator>Productivity in Tech RSS Generator</generator>
<rights>© 2017</rights>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/59a23435791e4b4e4e0e2f85</id>
  <title>Simple Ideas are Easier to Use and Implement</title>
  <updated>2017-08-27T02:53:41Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>When an idea strikes, we are often inspired to develop the idea into an elaborate project. In our minds this can add value to the project, but these "enhancements" often restrict the use case of the project and discourages engagement.</p>
<p>A great example of this was a workflow that I created for the writing app <a href="https://www.ulyssesapp.com">Ulysses</a>. I wanted to be able to create an outline or Table of Contents and have it create a Ulysses group (folder) and sheets for each section.</p>
<p>The workflow didn't take much time and after a bit of testing and tweaking, I was ready to share my creation with the <a href="https://productivityintech.com/join">Premium Members</a>.</p>
<h2>Problems with the First Version</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/1f2605608aeb4b00a4bbe659aef143b2">first version</a> of the of the workflow was nice, but there were a few issues that I knew I would need to address. The first was that in order to run the workflow, you would need to create the outline in Ulysses, copy the sheet identifier, and then run the workflow. Once it was finished, you then had to open Ulysses again and add the original outline to the new group.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/IMG_2286.67a0cb617a8a448a81c6f1fde137e78e.GIF" /></p>
<p>While I was fine with this workflow, but after sharing, there were a few people that ran into problems with running the workflow.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/1503799173.png" />
You see I had written the program based my usage and shared with without thinking about how others my run the workflow.</p>
<h2>The Fix</h2>
<p>In the <a href="https://workflow.is/workflows/1f2605608aeb4b00a4bbe659aef143b2">second version</a> of the workflow, I removed lines that only accepted Ulysses as the input. This made it so that you could load your text from any iOS app. By doing thing I was also able to fix the issue with the original content not being added to the sheet as well (without any pesky duplication).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://productivityintech.com/files/images/IMG_2292.GIF" /></p>
<p>I had introduced extra complexity and, because of that, the workflow wasn't simple enough to figure out. By taking another look, I was able to make the workflow more useful for me (and others) and also fixed issues that I was creating for myself.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://productivityintech.com/files/images/B&amp;A_ulysses_toc_workflow.png" /></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/59a23435791e4b4e4e0e2f85" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/59a0cf86791e4b4759931cfe</id>
  <title>Why my Episodes No Longer have Episode Numbers</title>
  <updated>2017-08-26T01:31:50Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p><em>Its a Sunday at 3pm...</em>
I should be relaxing but instead I'm deep into code. Not <em>"new exciting code that will revolutionize the productivity industry as we know it!</em>", mostly just refactoring. the art of making old code <em>more efficient</em>. Mostly just deleting lines of code like the ones in the image below.</p>
<p><img alt="Removing Episode Numbers from My Code" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/remove_ep_numbers.png" /></p>
<p>I recently made the decision that PIT was going to be going through some changes. One of those changes was the removal of its episode number system from the <em>Productivity in Tech Podcast</em>.</p>
<p>While episode numbers are a normal part of podcasts, I feel like adding them to the PIT episodes creates a false sense of success and  discourages exploration into older episodes.</p>
<h2>Shifting the Mindset</h2>
<p>At Apple's latest WWDC, it was announced that  Apple's feed spec (the most commonly used) was going to add new features like <a href="https://sixcolors.com/post/2017/06/apple-makes-major-podcast-updates/">episode classifications and whether you should listen to the latest episode or start at the beginning.</a></p>
<p>I feel like the PIT Podcast isn't made for either. While you can stay up to date with the latest episodes <strong>released every Monday</strong>, its our goal to ensure that we have an episode that fits the situation you may be in. <em>Obviously, we can't cover everything</em> but I want to focus on as many issues as possible. (You can let me know what topics you'd be interested in by using the hashtag #PITQuestions on <a href="https://twitter.com/prodintech" title="Twitter Profile - Prodintech">twitter</a>)</p>
<p>You will see an emphasis on this more and more throughout the site. I hope that you feel more encouraged to look for episodes that call to you and check connect with some of the amazing  professionals that we have worked with in the show.</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/59a0cf86791e4b4759931cfe" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/599a5df4791e4be8d2cfa6b9</id>
  <title>Website Redesigns Help Maintain the Mission</title>
  <updated>2017-08-21T04:13:40Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Nothing is ever perfect for me. The <em>Productivity in Tech</em> website is no different. As my mood changes so does my ideas on what makes good design. This is why I made the decision to not use a template and instead build my site to my liking from the ground up.</p>
<p>Now this is a very unproductive task, but it allows me to do something that is extremely valuable. Every time I'm modifying the look and feel of my website, I am reminding myself of how the look is supposed to reflect the brand.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/pit-website-concept.jpg" title="Early PIT Concept" />
The website has changed its look over the past 18 months but one thing remains the same. Productivity in Tech will always be passionate about bringing you content that provides authentic and realistic help in achieving more in your life! So while I may be distracted from time to time, it's important that I remember that goal any way I can.</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/599a5df4791e4be8d2cfa6b9" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/59912c6e791e4b4ee5856ebc</id>
  <title>Monthly (or More) Newsletter Posts for Premium Members</title>
  <updated>2017-08-14T04:51:58Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>I'm only going to post to the newsletter regularly for the pit premium members once a month. The newsletter will have some information about PIT and things that I'm interested in from a productivity standpoint.</p>
<p>It will go to their email, but will also be posted in the PIT premium slack team.</p>
<p>Signup to become a <a href="https://productivityintech.com/premium">Premium Member</a></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/59912c6e791e4b4ee5856ebc" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/59912c5e791e4b4eb830e0be</id>
  <title>It's always 1 or 0</title>
  <updated>2017-08-14T04:51:42Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>In the tech world, 1's and 0's are everything. It is a matter of "Yes" or "No", or "On" and "Off". Many people like to examine the world as a bunch of possibilities. There are many options available to you other than just yes and no. </p>
<p>Well Sort of... </p>
<p>I was reminded of this by watching <em>Mr. Robot</em>. In Episode 2, Mr. Robot unveils a part of his secret plan. When Elliot pushes back on the request, Mr. Robot delivers the ultimatum. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Sure, there are grays, but when you come right down to it, at its core, beneath every choice there's either a 1 or a 0. Either you do something or you don't."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Mr. Robot's lack of compassion is questionable but his idea behind choosing a course of action is spot on. When we make a choice, no matter that decision is, we are saying 1 (Yes) to something and 0 (No) to other things.  We have two things that we must do.
1. We must look at all the consequences of our decisions
2. be okay with accepting that we have chosen  those consequences. </p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/59912c5e791e4b4eb830e0be" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5955d85f791e4b82a4901a76</id>
  <title>How to Get Back Into the Swing of Things After a Hard Time</title>
  <updated>2017-06-30T04:49:35Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Every couple of years or so I get a visit from my family. This is the first year that I've been deliberate about my productivity. This was also the first week in a long time that I didn't think about <em>Productivity in Tech</em> before almost everything else. The <em>Be More Productive Show</em> didn't air this week. <em>Loosely Connected</em> aired a week late. I didn't blog or record at all for two weeks. This week was all about my mom, dad, and my sister. It was about having a great time with them creating as many memories as possible to last until the next time I would see them. </p>
<p>Today I dropped them off at the bus depot. I'm sad to see them gone, but this is a life that I am used to. Now it is my wife, my dogs, and I. Now it is back to normalcy and getting into the swing of things. </p>
<p>I have prepared my spread for July. I've recorded the videos and will begin editing so they can be released on the first. I've queued up questions for video content and I'm really excited to back into the swing of things with <em>PIT</em>. Still, I am having a hard time shaking the emptiness feeling.</p>
<p><img alt="Sad Dog" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/sad_dog.png" /></p>
<h2>Be Realistic About Your Expectations</h2>
<p>If you are dealing with something like loss or a major shift in thought remember to take things slow. Be sure to let people know what's going on and set realistic expectations for yourself and others. If you don't, then you can really get into a funk that is very had to recover from. (check out <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitreflections/42">PIT Reflection 42</a> to see what that looks like). </p>
<h2>Write about how you feel</h2>
<p>I often find comfort in getting the thoughts out of my head. I personally use <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">Day One</a> to catalog my thoughts. It's good to hold onto these feelings and revisit them when you get into a similar funk.</p>
<p>Another suggestion would be to share how you feel with others. This will help you build a support network that will not only help you, but you will be able to help later on.</p>
<h2>Remember What You are Working Towards</h2>
<p><img alt="The Sun will Shine Again" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/dawn-sunset-person-woman.png" /></p>
<p>It takes time but you will recover. You will get better. How do you get back into the swing of things. One step at a time. Soon I will be achieving the goals that I have for my life, and that will allow me to spend more time with my family and do more of the things that bring me joy. </p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5955d85f791e4b82a4901a76" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5948ae2a791e4b4706ed712f</id>
  <title>Growth Through Sharing (and a Little EDM)</title>
  <updated>2017-06-20T05:10:02Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <h1>Growth Through Sharing (and a Little EDM)</h1>
<p>Perhaps the most stressful thing to think about when making a video for our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCw9MKaVM-8EPNyhW3VYVacQ">YouTube channel</a> is figuring out the background music.</p>
<p>In fact licensing music is super stressful as it's hard to figure out what you are supposed to do with rights and all that stuff. This is why I was super excited when I discovered that the sensational electronic music label <a href="https://www.monstercat.com/licensing/youtube-policy">Monster Cat has an amazing licensing strategy</a> that lets you utilize all of their music for FREE*. This is why PIT Videos in the future will feature music primarily from MonsterCat.</p>
<p><img alt="monstercat.com" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/monstercat.png" /></p>
<p>MonsterCat's reasoning was this: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Monstercat and its artists are gamers! We have invested thousands of hours of our lives destroying zombies, building elaborate worlds, raiding end-game bosses, levelling up etc. It is a very large part of our lives! In saying this, understand that we love the videos (machinimas, walk-throughs, montages etc.) that many of you create!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By doing this they are not only making their music available to more people, by widening their network. They are also investing into the communities that they are also interested in. </p>
<p>PIT is passionate about productivity, but we don't know everything about the vast topic. That's why we rely on productivity and tech professionals and catalog their insight in our <a href="https://facebook.com/prodintech">facebook</a> community and <a href="http://productivityintech.com/podcasts">podcasts</a>. In fact our entire business model is designed on the idea of sharing what we have and who we know. And in MonsterCat fashion we aim to give away as much of that information as possible. While this means we rely mostly on <a href="https://patreon.com/productivityintech">patronage</a> to cover our expenses we are able to get our message out and work with amazing professionals! </p>
<p>If you are hoping to grow your community or brand, consider allowing to giving the world a taste of what you have to offer. </p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/black%20and%20red%20present.png" /></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5948ae2a791e4b4706ed712f" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/593e9d44791e4b6759240b9b</id>
  <title>Weekly Recap, June 5-11, 2017</title>
  <updated>2017-06-12T13:55:16Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <h1>Weekly Recap for June 5-11, 2017</h1>
<h2>Podcasts</h2>
<p>We have a great set of episodes this week. It kicked off with an interview with the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitpodcast/62">Mad Scientist of the Internet</a>. We also announced that the PIT Podcast will be going on a bi-weekly episode schedule and hinted about a <strong>New Project</strong> coming out in the next week or so</p>
<p>Then following the <em>WWDC</em> Keynote event we released a special <a href="https://patreon.com/productivityintech">patrons-only</a> episode of Loosely-Connected. Don't worry, we released a regular <a href="http://productivityintech.com/loosely_connected/12">LC episode</a> on Thursday.</p>
<p><img alt="Loosely Connected" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/loosely_connected_logo_500.png" /></p>
<h2>Blog Posts</h2>
<p>Have you just ever not been in the mood to get things done. Don't worry it happens. Being able to recognize those times and knowing what to do. That's why we wrote a <a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/5938da30791e4b528e168b70"><em>Practical Guide to Overcome Not Feeling It</em></a></p>
<p>We also talked about the popular podcast playing app <a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/593b854f791e4be3de83d07d"><strong>Castro</strong></a> and a <a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/593d897d791e4bf8b98b8d9d">few productivity tricks we learned from the late great Adam West</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="Castro app" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Castro-banner.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Videos</h2>
<p>There was a lot of chatter from our professionals. Even though we didn't release any videos there was enough content to go around from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/cesidalessio">Francesco</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCE_lTvaMHuco_Oh3-69LkCA">Carl</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCl8eugrGayFDPRZ9TwxDOCw">Enrico</a>.</p>
<div style="position:relative;height:0;padding-bottom:75.0%"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ekINZgo364I?ecver=2" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;width:100%;height:100%;left:0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<h2>Books and Reading</h2>
<p>I've really been enjoying reading <a href="http://amzn.to/2ra3OkQ"><em>Die Empty</em></a> by Todd Henry. I've also been working my way through Malcom Gladwell's <em><a href="http://amzn.to/2raeQXc">The Tipping Point</a></em> </p>
<p><img alt="Die Empty" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/die_empty.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>That's it for this week. Of course there was a lot of great information in the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/fb">Facebook group</a> as well. I hope that you be on the look out for more great content from Productivity in Tech!</strong></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/593e9d44791e4b6759240b9b" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/593d897d791e4bf8b98b8d9d</id>
  <title>Holy Productivity Batman! - RIP Adam West</title>
  <updated>2017-06-11T18:18:37Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <h1>Holy Productivity Batman! - RIP Adam West</h1>
<p>For those that may have not heard yet, <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/adam-west-dead-batman-star-832264">Adam West recent passed away</a>. West was the first Batman I remember. In fact, he served as the shining example of heroism for several generations of people. I wanted to share a few of the many things that I thought about while reflecting on the amazing life and career of the <em>caped crusader</em>. </p>
<h2>Batman was always equipped for any situation</h2>
<p>We rarely see Batman without his utility belt. The benefit to being a billionaire vigilante is that he was always equipped with the tech (or the ability to create it) needed to defeat his foes.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://68.media.tumblr.com/fb160e67657a4fcc0eaa94df87461ff6/tumblr_nne5shPRWF1s2wio8o1_500.gif" /></p>
<p>In many of the challenges that we face today, be sure that you are equipped with the tools needed to overcome any obstacle. Your utility belt probably won't have a built in radio, grappling hook or smoke bombs. Instead it can be your notebook and pen or your favorite productivity app. Be careful though; <em>Bat-er-rangs</em> are illegal in some states.</p>
<h2>Batman had an amazing team</h2>
<p>When you think of batman, it's hard not to include Batgirl,  Robin, or his trusty butler Alfred. This team was by Batman's side providing the help that certainly he needed in many situations. </p>
<p>You most likely have an amazing team with you as well. They can be your support line or your backup when called upon. Just make sure your costume always looks better (sorry Robin).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://68.media.tumblr.com/04a64d889fcf7eb500b26843c34e3b9d/tumblr_ooyw9ndCxd1ultu3qo1_400.gif" /></p>
<h2>Batman never gave up, no matter the circumstances</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>"Failure is what happens when you've decided that you've failed" - Tim S. Grover, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1476714207/?tag=kjaymiller-20"><em>Relentless</em></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This defines the premise of almost every premise of Batman. Most of the time just as <em>Joker</em> or <em>Penguin</em> thought they had one. Batman (usually with the help of something that Robin said) would have a flash of inspiration that would not only save them from some tough situation, but they would go on to foil the evil-doer's plot.</p>
<p><img alt="A few of Batman's many foes" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/batman-villains.png" /></p>
<p>While we are rarely, strapped to table with some ray gun pointed at us or seconds away from being dipped into boiling magma, our lives are filled with many situations in which we don't know how we will overcome the adversity. Remember that giving up and accepting your impending defeat is the only way to ensure that you will not win. </p>
<p>I guess what I'm trying to say is, <strong>Don't Stop, Don't Quit, EVER!</strong></p>
<h2>West was more than just Batman but will be always be remembered as him.</h2>
<p>We all remember West for being the onomatopoetic <em>Batman</em>, but he was much more than that. In fact, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001842/?ref_=fn_al_nm_1">IMDB credits West with 193 roles</a>.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f5/Adam_West_Batman_1966.jpg/473px-Adam_West_Batman_1966.jpg" /></p>
<p>This reminds that we are often known for one/few things in our life, but that doesn't define who we are. Whether you are a scientist, a mother, or just someone who is always doing something different (me 🙋🏾‍♂️), be sure to not let what people call or define you as limit your ability to enjoy life!</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/593d897d791e4bf8b98b8d9d" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/593b854f791e4be3de83d07d</id>
  <title>Your Self-Curated Podcast Playlist with Castro</title>
  <updated>2017-06-10T05:36:15Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Johan Gustaphzon</name>
<email>gustaphzon@gmx.com</email>
<uri>http://appleyra.se</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p><img alt="Castro banner" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Castro-banner.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p><a href="http://supertop.co/castro/">Castro</a> is developed by the dynamic duo <a href="https://twitter.com/padraig">Pádraig Ó Cinnéide</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/prendio2">Oisín Prendiville</a> better known as <em><a href="">Supertop</a></em>. </p>
<p>Castro is divided into four parts which all can be accessed from icons in the bottom of the screen. In this post, we'll start from the right and work our way to the end. </p>
<h2>Discover</h2>
<p>You can find or add podcasts in the <em>Discover</em> tab by name, URL, or from the top charts divided into categories. Although the charts are from the United States by default, you can choose other countries as well (by changing the settings). </p>
<p>Tapping on a show reveals more information. From that page, you can see the artwork and a description for that podcast, and view the oldest and newest episodes. You can directly subscribe from that page as well. By tapping on an episode, you get a menu with options to stream, add to your queue, or mark it as a favourite episode. There is also an arrow to the right which leads to the show description and and show notes. Tapping between the oldest and newest episodes lists all episodes. This allows you to subscribe to the show or just listen to some episodes.  </p>
<h2>Inbox</h2>
<p>All the new episodes from your subscribed podcasts ends up in the <em>Inbox</em>. When you have a new episode a blue badge will show up over the icon, Similar to apps on the home screen of your phone. Manipulating shows and podcasts are the same as on the <em>Discover</em> page. Tap on the episode to show a menu. Instead of "mark as favorite", you can archive that episode. This is the place where you select what you want to listen to and add it to the queue. </p>
<p><img alt="Inbox, Queue and Archive &amp; Castro" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Inbox-Queue-och-Archive-i-Castro.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Queue</h2>
<p>An episode automatically starts to download once added to the Queue. Downloading preferences can be adjusted in the settings. The dots to the right of each episode allows you to drag and reorder your queue. </p>
<h2>Archive</h2>
<p>The archive contains all your "starred" and subscribed podcasts. There's also a complete history of what you listened to. This is a great place to start if you looking for an old episode. </p>
<p><img alt="Show notes, Summary &amp; iMessage in Castro" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Show-notes-Summary-och-iMessage-i-Castro.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Now playing</h2>
<p>A mini player appears at the bottom (below the icons) as soon as you start playing an episode. Tapping the arrow to the left opens a bigger player which has a speed adjustment and and share sheet, as well as the option to set a sleep timer. In the latest version they added buttons for <em>continuous playback</em> and <em>Enhanced audio</em>. Enhanced audio is great when listening to podcast on the bus or tram. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, this screen lacks cover art. It can distract you with the scrolling long titles. </p>
<p>The playing time indicator is a sound wave. The animation in the sound wave is somewhat jerky and not nice. <em>Castro</em>  lack the ability to remove silence.</p>
<h2>Other features</h2>
<p>There is a setting to send new episodes from your favorite podcasts immediately to the queue without passing the inbox. Also, tapping on a shared link from Castro makes it possible to add that episode to your queue without subscribing to the podcast. </p>
<p>Castro also has a gorgeous dark theme. You can easily switch between themes by swiping two fingers up or down. This makes it easy to change theme regardless of where you are in the app. </p>
<p>Searching is done on Castros server and resulting in less data and battery usage. The app also have support for iMessage which makes it even easier to share episodes.</p>
<p>Castro is a well made app with many smart features. For people who follow many different podcast and jump around between single episodes, Castro is the best app on the market.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/castro-play-share-podcasts/id1080840241?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=10lKZy&amp;ct=pit"><em>Castro</em> — Play and Share Podcasts - App Store</a> [$ 4.99]</strong></p>
<div style="position:relative;height:0;padding-bottom:75.0%"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/agVUjPjt8yA?ecver=2" width="480" height="360" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;width:100%;height:100%;left:0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

<p><span> video by Supertop </span></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/593b854f791e4be3de83d07d" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5938da30791e4b528e168b70</id>
  <title>The Practical Guide to Overcome "Not Feeling It"</title>
  <updated>2017-06-08T05:01:36Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <h1>The Practical Guide to Overcome "Not Feeling It"</h1>
<p>Do you know anyone that just always seems happy, motivated, and productive. They suck don't they? Just kidding, I'm really just jealous. But Seriously?! Who is that great all the time.</p>
<p>When I started writing this, I wasn't really <em>feeling it</em>. In fact, I didn't even know "Not Feeling IT"  was going to be my topic. Since I couldn't think of anything else to write, I thought "why not?" and started writing. Of course there are plenty of blog posts that give you the feel "goodie goodie" approach to getting out of your "rainy day mood". If you are anything like me, the last thing you really want to do when you aren't feeling "cheery" is listen to other people who are so damn happy it should be illegal. Here are a few tips that I normally use to find the energy to accomplish my tasks. </p>
<h2>Go for a Run or Lift Something</h2>
<p>When you are feeling a little agitated, there's not better time to use that pent up rage to punch, lift, kick and run it all out. </p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/workout-20170707.png" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3025957/what-happens-to-our-brains-when-we-exercise-and-how-it-makes-us-happier">When we workout, our body gives off endorphins that can help lift your spirit</a>. Runners have referred to this as a <em>runner's high</em>. </p>
<p>It also can help your mind get out of the funk that it's in and provide a source of inspiration. This is why many <a href="https://mymorningroutine.com/morning-exercise/#continue">successful entrepreneurs always make time for their morning workout</a>.  </p>
<h2>Check what you are Listening to</h2>
<p>Many will argue how music can affects your mood, but most will agree, it does something. As outlined in <a href="http://www.healthline.com/health-news/mental-listening-to-music-lifts-or-reinforces-mood-051713#1">this <em>Healthline</em> article</a>, while sad music can negatively impact some people, it can serve as a form of therapy for others and even lift spirits in many.</p>
<p>There are also many sounds and songs that can you focus. I recommend listening to many different genres of music and see what sounds have a positive and negative affect on your mood.</p>
<p>If you aren't feeling all too great, play that song or album that gets you motivated. I recommend creating a "Let's Do This!" playlist that you can rely on to pull out of a negative space.</p>
<p><img alt="Music Can be just the tool you need. " src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/listing-to-music-20170707.png" /></p>
<p>It's also good technique to pair your playlist with your morning workout.</p>
<h2>Change Your Scene or Try Something New</h2>
<p>Does your office space look like the Batcave minus the super awesome computer, costumes and gadgets? Proper lighting can make your brain feel more alert. If Lighting is not the problem, try changing your scenery. Studies show that your brain goes into a <em>panic</em> alert and <em>absorption</em> mode that can kick you into high gear when you do something or go somewhere that it doesn't expect. I recommend having four or five go to spots that you can really start getting work done.  </p>
<p>Another thing to try is anything that you've never done before. This will get you thinking in whole new ways and provide some inspiration.</p>
<p>Routines are great for muscle memory but suck when it comes to creativity and passion. Always be challenging yourself to bigger and better things.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/colorful-hill-20170707.png" /></p>
<h2>Remember Why You're Doing Whatever You're Doing</h2>
<p>We often lose sight of our goals when we're in the middle of it. This is similar to when you decide to start working out. </p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Week 1</strong>
"Yes I lost 6 pounds already!😌"</p>
<p><strong>Week 2</strong>
"Alright another 4 pounds!💪🏾"</p>
<p><strong>Week 3</strong>
"WTF! I gained a pound😰"</p>
<p><strong>Week 4</strong>
"Only 1 pound lost! What's going on? Why am I even wasting my time!😤"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even though your scale may not show you the changes, you are probably a bit more energetic, and your little pockets of flab will start slowly shrinking. Meanwhile you are ignoring that and losing hope because the changes are so small you don't notice them. </p>
<p>This is how we feel in our work as well. We notice the early big changes but the smaller (or seemingly adverse) or progress gets, the more we begin to stop noticing them at all and start feeling like we aren't really succeeding.</p>
<p>A good way to prevent this from happening is to <a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/5928f2b6791e4bb00bf7cca0">keep track of your small wins</a>. This allows you to look at the growing list of accomplishments and see the progress that you've been making over time.</p>
<h2>Be Okay With not Being Okay</h2>
<p>No one (I mean no one) is <em>feeling it</em> 24/7. You have to be okay with that. If you've done all of these things and you still can't  shake the rut. If you feel like you desperately need to recoup, give yourself some time to recover. Don't wallow in your misery but get away from it all and just relax a bit. If you don't take care of yourself in these little moments, you will find only find yourself in more ruts.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/good-day-cup-20170707.png" /></p>
<h2>Keep Working Through It!</h2>
<p>Okay so in the end I wound up being a bit more "chipper" than I thought. It would seem that just working through the rut was enough to pull me out of it.</p>
<p>So I hope that in reading this you have gotten a few ideas on how to make it through your rut. I wasn't feeling it when I started writing this, but I became absorbed into the work and I was focused and motivated by the time it was done!</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5938da30791e4b528e168b70" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5930e35b791e4b6b0733d7bb</id>
  <title>Recap the Week: May 29 - June 2, 2017</title>
  <updated>2017-06-02T23:30:00Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Here's a recap of all the great content PIT put out for the week of May 29th, 2017</p>
<h2>Podcast Episodes</h2>
<p>It all started with the Memorial Day Holiday. I thought I would treat you to a special episode with my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/DumbbellsDragon">Ken Rotter</a> from <a href="https://dumbbellsanddragons.com/">Dumbbells and Dragons.</a> </p>
<p><img alt="Interview with Kenneth Rotter" src="http://gallery.tinyletterapp.com/2d7f3965faca67f66d3a6d633548111c5c1898ad/images/8989b612-0475-4f61-9674-c5ac3a214d88.jpg" /></p>
<p>I also took the extra time that I had off to release a little <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitreflections/63">PITReflection</a> as well.  </p>
<h2>Videos</h2>
<p>I made videos than usual this week as well. </p>
<ul>
<li>On Monday I spoke a little bit about the <a href="https://youtu.be/0dTaV9Bpk7o">communities I'm a part of</a>. </li>
<li>Thursday I release <strong>TWO</strong> videos - one showcasing my <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCw9MKaVM-8EPNyhW3VYVacQ">Bullet Journal spread for the month of June</a>, and the other breaking down <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCw9MKaVM-8EPNyhW3VYVacQ">my monthly focus for the month</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="My Monthly Focus is FOCUS" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/focus-june.png" /></p>
<h2>Blog Posts</h2>
<p>The writing has been amazing. I've taken more time this week than I have all year just to get my thoughts down and share them with you!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/592cc9bb791e4b56e59f84d9">I shared my really small win with you!</a></li>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/592cc9bb791e4b56e59f84d9">I explain a theory about making your all your systems similar</a></li>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog/5930d377791e4b4c38ac6f5a">I explain how I've been putting social media in the <em>Friend Zone</em></a></li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="A very simple win is still a win" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/tic-tac-toe-hearts.jpeg" /></p>
<p>I also got the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/files/feed.xml">atom feed</a> back online and would love if you subscribed to it! </p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5930e35b791e4b6b0733d7bb" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5930d377791e4b4c38ac6f5a</id>
  <title>Putting Social Media in the Friend Zone</title>
  <updated>2017-06-01T19:54:47Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <h1>Putting Social Media in the "Friend Zone"</h1>
<p>Social media has its teeth locked into the world. The ability to <strong>legally stalk people</strong> (I mean it's called “following") and potentially be famous tugs at our natural instincts. Every wolf wants to follow the alpha and one day either mate with it or become it.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/tumblr.png" /></p>
<p>This is the where I join the scene: obsessing over the professionals in the productivity space and trying to create my own tribe of productive people and provide as much value to them as I possibly can. These things are great but the “value” that I am trying to bring cannot be achieved worrying about the reach that my content will have.</p>
<p>So why do I do it? Why do I enroll in follower management tools to track the growth and decline in my popularity. Why do I think about "buzzwords" and "SEO optimized" traffic.</p>
<p><strong>Because I gauge the value of what I create based on what others think of it and not my satisfaction of it.</strong></p>
<p>That needs to stop.</p>
<h2>Breaking up with Social</h2>
<p>How many times have you heard “I’m quitting (insert social media platform here)!”? (Which they feel compelled to post on facebook instead of just disappearing.) This unhealthy reliance on social media will often lead to someone saying they are quitting the stuff for good! I said it to when I dropped off of facebook for more than a year to focus on my community and podcast (and Twitter). </p>
<p>It is virtually impossible to "eliminate" social media from our lives. I have given up on ridding my life of social media. Now I  am here to "Define the Relationship" (DTR). </p>
<h2>The Friend Zone</h2>
<p>I had a crushes on two of my closest friends. The first was in middle school. I didn't reveal this to her until after I had moved away and knew that there was no chance in Hell that we would ever be a "thing". The second time was my senior year of high school. Unfortunately she had a thing for another friend of ours and he reciprocated that affection. Both times I heard the phrase that no pubescent teenage boy want's to hear. </p>
<p>"I just see you more a brother"</p>
<p>While it was awkward at first and our friendship did my friend's eyes. I would forever be <strong>Just a Friend</strong>. </p>
<p><img alt="Just Friends?" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/just-friends.png" /></p>
<h2>Friend Zoning Social Media</h2>
<p>Do you let your friends, interrupt your time at work? Do you let them take you away from things that you really want to just enjoy. Do you let them get in the way of your career and your passions. If you do, I would suggest setting boundaries with them first and then continue reading. </p>
<p>When you define the relationship that you have with social media, you it's control over you away. If you are jumping on Twitter and Instagram to connect with your friends, why not put the entire network in that zone.</p>
<p>Here are a few ways to help put social in the friend zone.</p>
<h3>Have One Place that You Hang Out with Social Media</h3>
<p>Some friends you just can't take to the library with you and others you don't ever take to the bar. NEVER! You love your friends but they can tend to make a fool out of themselves (and sometimes you) in certain areas. </p>
<p>Treat social media in this way. Decide to only check social media at home. This allows you to enjoy the moment without the interruptions and excessive notifications. Don't even keep the app, on your phone. Afraid you are missing out of something. In fact they are missing out on your amazing experiences. If you want to capture the moment to share with your friends, I recommend you take photos and upload them later. If you have a witty thought to tweet. Save it in an application like <a href="http://agiletortoise.com/drafts/">Drafts App</a> and share them with the world you get home.</p>
<h3>Make it an "Us Only" Date</h3>
<p>My <a href="">brother-in-law</a> and I will occasionally get dinner together. Some days we get monster wings or slices of pizza topped to the brim. Other days, we stop at the nearest Burger King and eat $1.50 Chicken Nuggets. No matter what is on the plate, we take time and just talk. We catch up with each other. We crack jokes and talk about things going on in our lives. It has become something that we often feel needs to happen. It is a special time for us.  When we leave the restaurant, we feel energized and ready for the upcoming adventures ahead.
<img alt="" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/bros01_Jun_2017.png" /></p>
<p>There are going to be times when we need the support of our social network. I suggest creating designated times to jump online and <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23justbesocial&amp;src=typd">#justbesocial</a>. Get involved in a weekly twitter chat or join a community that revolves around your favorite tv show. If neither of those things sound fun just tell yourself "after dinner I'm going to catch up with my friends. </p>
<p>Make this a sacred time where you absorb yourself into your network. When it's done feel happy and re-energized, but content until the next <em>date</em>.</p>
<h2>Set healthy boundaries</h2>
<p>Do you catch yourself spending 15-20 minutes in the bathroom scrolling through Instagram and losing track of time. Do you often feel restless and "too awake" at night before bed. Just like when your mother would make you get off the phone after 9PM, it's time you set some hard, but healthy, boundaries. </p>
<p>Make rules for yourself about when it is not the "right" time to be social. Here are a few of my rules.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>When eating dinner with my wife, I can't be on social media when she's at the table.</strong></li>
<li><strong>No more technology after 10:15</strong> except for Youtube watching with my wife before bed. Even then, only funny videos. </li>
<li><strong>No consuming social media when hanging out with others.</strong> Posting is okay but anything other than that is just rude. </li>
</ul>
<p>If you have problems telling yourself no. I recommend putting your devices into "Do not Use Mode". I use focus to block certain websites on my Mac after a certain time. I also use Forest and SleepTown on my phone to remind myself that I am not allowed to use my phone. </p>
<h2>Make New Friends</h2>
<p>I love my "online" friends, but I'm always looking for new ones. 
Meeting new people is fun! </p>
<p>I've also met many more by joining a few local communities. In fact I wrote this post while at a <a href="https://www.meetup.com/Shut-Up-Write-SDNC/events/240004303/">meet up for writers</a>. </p>
<p><img alt="Go Places, Meet People, Have Fun" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/meetup-on-rocks.png" /></p>
<p>When you do more and meet new people, this reduces the time you spend in front of social media apps. It also makes the time you do spend online more valuable as you strengthen the relationships with those whom you've just met.</p>
<h2>Replace your "Bad" Habits with Better Ones</h2>
<p>If you have gotten this far you may believe that your social media usage is starting to prevent you from doing things. When I  think of something that I should be doing instead of lurking on twitter or in the Facebook group, I stop and immediately start doing that thing for at least 5 minutes. One of two things will happen. </p>
<ol>
<li>I will struggle to do that thing for 5 minutes and then jump back on social media until the next thought arises. </li>
<li>(<strong>More Often</strong>) I will work well beyond the 5 minutes and wind up with something that I'm somewhat proud of and then share it on social media for my friends to enjoy!.</li>
</ol>
<p>This takes me from being a <em>consumer</em> and transforms me into a <em>producer</em>. I'm now using social media to help propel my career instead of stifling it. When I choose to socialize with friends through it, the interactions are more authentic and I have many more experiences to share with the crowd! </p>
<p>Do you remember those professionals that I mentioned earlier. I'm now building actual relationships with them. I'm becoming a professional myself. When I do use social media, it's with a sense of control now the relationship has been adequately defined. </p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5930d377791e4b4c38ac6f5a" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/592cc9bb791e4b56e59f84d9</id>
  <title>THEORY: Making Things Similar Help with Mental Fatigue</title>
  <updated>2017-05-29T18:24:11Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>I spent a lot of time today rewriting code. This code didn't change very much on the website. If you were to look at it quickly, you wouldn't notice much of a difference. Still these  changes made a lot of sense on my side as a developer. </p>
<p>In the development world, this called refactoring your code. It usually means optimizing the code without changing the appearance of the end result. This is usually done to make code easier to understand or more efficient. It can also be used to increase the performance of your program or make it conform to newer versions of the programming language. </p>
<p>The refactoring that was performed today was make the source code of the website look more like the <a href="https://github.com/kjaymiller/podcast_publisher">podcast_publisher</a>. Previously, I would have to shift my thoughts from the code for uploading files and podcasts and the website itself. This uniformity allows me to quickly transition between the codebases. </p>
<p>This was done as a way to help simplify the processes and mindsets in the automation of some podcast tasks. The need to do this was apparent after the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitreflections/63">unfortunate loss of an upcoming podcast episode</a>. My belief is that the more that my system is similar, <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/brain-wise/201209/the-true-cost-multi-tasking">the less mental energy is wasted on switching tasks</a>. </p>
<p>The changes in that manner make a big difference in the overall performance of all of the things that surround the website. This includes the more important podcasts, blog, and videos.</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/592cc9bb791e4b56e59f84d9" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/5928f2b6791e4bb00bf7cca0</id>
  <title>My Small Win and Why It's Important</title>
  <updated>2017-05-27T03:29:31Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Today I learned how to convert a string field into a DateTime field in MongoDB. </p>
<p>Now while those that don't know javascript (or anything about Mongo) are thinking "How does this apply to me, well it doesn't. Those that do know a bit more in the field may be thinking "Big woop, it's just a <code>forEach</code> call on each item that needs to be changed." You are right, it is a very basic level of knowledge in the field of javascript. The reason I'm so excited is that I don't know much javascript. In fact, until I started attending <a href="http://www.walljs.org">WEAllJS</a>, I wasn't doing very much javascript at all (even though many my JS developing friends have recommended I start learning)</p>
<p><img alt="A win is a win no matter how small" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/tic-tac-toe-hearts.jpeg" /></p>
<p>This was a <em>small win</em>. It was an extremely huge small win. You see the blog on the website had never been in order. This was because my code actually saved the blog posts dates as strings and not dates. (Basically like the difference between 1 and <em>one</em> in the eyes of the computer). I just lived with the problem because I didn't know how to fix it. However my journal only had one more task in it. In order to ensure that I completed that task I needed to make sure my posts were being listed in the right order.</p>
<p>That mean completing this tasks I'd been putting off for months.</p>
<p>I did the research and applied some logic. Finally I came up with the code that got everything fixed.</p>
<p><img alt="Not the Code but the Result of it" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/mongo-isodate.png" /></p>
<p><a href="http://amzn.to/2qsIEx6"><em>How to be Everything</em></a> author <a href="http://puttylike.com/about/">Emilie Wapnick</a> explains that logging the simple wins is a great way to motivate yourself to success in areas that you are not confident.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Tracking your small wins is a powerful way to combat the natural tendency toward negativity.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I'm staying positive and I'm taking care of business. And it will all start with one simple tweet (that I also logged in <a href="http://dayoneapp.com/">DayOne</a> where I have a <em>Small Wins</em> Journal!)
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TIL?src=hash">#TIL</a> how to convert strings to date time fields in MongoDB!</p>- Jay Miller (@kjaymiller) <a href="https://twitter.com/kjaymiller/status/868304451827777536">May 27, 2017</a></blockquote> <script  src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/5928f2b6791e4bb00bf7cca0" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/590939df791e4b80a19cf65d</id>
  <title>Not Your Granddad (or anyone else's) Productivity</title>
  <updated>2017-05-03T02:01:00Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>My grandfather was hands-down the largest inspiration to me. I have so many fond memories of experiences and lessons that contribute to the time I have spent with him. There is Just One Problem.</p>
<h3>I'm not my Grandfather</h3>
<p>While I am a productivity scholar, my grandfather was into mathematics to the point that that is the only hobby I can recall he has. This obsession has been only absorbed for the sake of knowing it; I apply my knowledge with the intent of teaching more people in the tech space like me the same tricks (saving more people time and energy at an exponential level). Furthermore, I have applied side hustle that makes (currently) no money and a full-time job that funds it. For my entire life, my grandfather has been not retired, but rather intentionally unemployed. This gave him more time to devote to me. </p>
<p>When I look at the relationship that I had with my grandmother,  who left retirement for part time work seems terribly unbalanced. She was a hard worker for several long and painful years and has toughed it out through the worst of socio-political climates for African Americans. She has held many hobbies and has done as much as she had time to do for me, even though she knew I preferred the company of my grandfather. </p>
<p>The truth is simple. While my grandfather helped to mold me into the person that I am today, my grandmother had more similarities and perhaps qualifications to do so. </p>
<p><img alt="Escorting my Grandmother on my Wedding Day" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/grandmother.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Who Are You Giving an Opportunity to Speak</h2>
<p>I write this to think about this in my current pursuit of knowledge in the productivity space. Of course the opinions of the productivity "Professionals" are easy to acquire and vetted by the loud spoken majority. It is the current achiever with her head down that holds fantastic secrets to success. Find new and often disregarded voices to listen to and grow in ways that make you stand out from the crowd.</p>
<p>This was one of the reasons I started the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitpodcast">Productivity in Tech Podcast</a>. It was to give equal value to the opinions of those being productive as a profession as well as those who were simply just being productive to achieve the quality of work and life that they hold today. </p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/590939df791e4b80a19cf65d" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/590181ba791e4bdf2a7a4e36</id>
  <title>Simplifying PIT</title>
  <updated>2017-04-27T05:29:30Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Having just finished the <a href="http://amzn.to/2p65ld6">Accidental Creative</a>, I was extremely motivated to align my focus with my vocation (not my occupation). </p>
<p>This idea is that my occupation (job) can be anything that inspires my vocation (calling). </p>
<p>My calling is to be one of providing insight to others in a shared way that benefits the many.</p>
<p>Lately there has been a big push to figure out how to monetize Productivity in Tech. This has been a difficult thing for me because at the heart of PIT is the desire to provide as much content for free. This self-imposed requirement means that I'm limited in the way that I can provide content. Still I somehow find myself wanting to do more and more for the community. </p>
<p>As I'm writing this there are 9 different areas that I am trying to present content. </p>
<h3>All the "things" that Jay is Managing</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/podcasts">PITPodcast</a></li>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/loosely_connected">Loosely Connected</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCw9MKaVM-8EPNyhW3VYVacQ">Daily PIT Videos</a> (and the occaisional productivity inspired video)</li>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog">Blogs Posts</a> (whenever I can get them out)</li>
<li><a href="https://reddit.com/r/productivityintech">SubReddit</a> chock full of links around the productivity space.</li>
<li><a href="http://productivityintech.com/join">Social Media</a> posts for all the stuff I'm doing</li>
<li>The constantly growing <a href="http://productivityintech.com/fb">Facebook Group</a></li>
<li>Occaisional Site Maintenance and Updates</li>
<li>A <a href="http://bit.ly/pit-newsletter-archive">weekly newsletter</a> bringing you the best in all of these </li>
</ul>
<p>I'll save you the breakdown of each one. After looking at my (colorful) list of these things, my eyes were opened to the reality of things. </p>
<h1>I'M DOING TOO MUCH</h1>
<p><img alt="Simplify Pit" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/simplify_pit.jpg" /></p>
<p>It's sucks to admin but I can't work at this pace. I'm on the path to burnout. I need to figure out something. </p>
<p>I have decided that I will making some strategic moves on my end to reduce my workload without compromising the quality of the content that is being put out. </p>
<h2>Give up Control</h2>
<p>The biggest thing that I'm doing is taking a back seat on the Facebook Group. </p>
<p>The beautiful thing about the Facebook group is that the community makes it what it is. </p>
<p>There is very little value added by me in comparison to the plethora of links, questions, and amazing conversations that are held there. </p>
<p>I will become a "member of this group" instead of promoter. I believe that the group will continue to grow on it's own without much promotion from me. </p>
<p>This reduces the amount of mental strain on me.</p>
<h2>Automate Your Reach</h2>
<p>I HATE AUTOMATED SOCIAL MEDIA. In fact I have vowed to ensure that my personal account is free of any automated DM's and posts (so much that it broke my IFTTT integrations). </p>
<p>I have to accept the fact that my PIT social media accounts (save instagram) do not get the reach that a primary account has. It is for that reason I will be manning my personal accounts again and using the PIT accounts to share content on social media. </p>
<p>I will not, however, </p>
<ul>
<li>sharing quotes all the time (unless I just read them from a book or heard them on a podcast. Any other way is a form of social diarrhea 💩).</li>
<li>give you the same tweet again and again. Only relevant and timely posts. </li>
<li>fill your timeline with "HEY BUY MY STUFF!!" Posts. I will promote but I will do it without spamming.</li>
<li>Send "<em>Thanks for following</em>" posts or dm's (again social 💩)</li>
</ul>
<p>This will allow me to be more personal with my account. Occaisionally, I will make a personal reply but the majority of my social usage of the PIT accounts will be for announcements of content. </p>
<p>This is to say that I will continue to post productivity inspired photos on the PIT instagram. I really enjoy doing that and it has become my personal account (I don't even check my personal anymore so follow <a href="https://instagram.com/prodintech">PIT on IG</a>)</p>
<h2>Collect to be Ready</h2>
<p>I haven't seriously professed my love for InoReader until now. InoReader is an amazing tool that lets me look at what I'm interested in and very little else in the Productivity Space.</p>
<p>One of the great things that it supports is folder and tag management with Rules. This means that I can tell inoreader to do things with posts before I ever look at them. </p>
<p><img alt="Inoreader-Add-to-Reddit" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/Inoreader-Add-to-Reddit.png" /></p>
<p>By doing this (and a little magic from <em>IFTTT</em>) I am able to add productivity posts directly to the SubReddit. Of course there will be the occasional weird post that slips in but I've noticed that the continual growth of the subreddit with little interaction leads me to believe that people are using it as a curated resource. This means that I can provide more content in this manner which will save me time in the long run. </p>
<p>Another example is the collection of the newsletter content. By going through my newsletter candidates (my starred items) and having them visible in my dashboard makes it easy for me to grab the latest news for the newsletter instead of searching all over the place. This will greatly reduce the amount of time spent on the newsletter. </p>
<h2>Same Amount of Work All Together Takes Less Time</h2>
<p>Do you know the story of Sisyphus. He's the one that was tasked with pushing the boulder up the mountain. Seriously, his job sucks.</p>
<p>The but if you've ever had to push something somewhere. You know that getting started is the hardest part. </p>
<p>If fact it takes about 15 minutes to meet a state of flow and a 45 minutes to hit the peak of that state.</p>
<p>Doing the Youtube videos every day makes it very hard to ever reach a flow state. In fact that 5 minute video takes about 45 minutes to record, edit, and publish. My hypothesis (which I will be tested next week) is that I can record all 5 segments at one time and release them as one video in about 1/3 of the total time it would take for me to do each one individually. </p>
<p><strong>Old Way</strong> - 45 minutes/per video * 5 videos = <strong>225 minutes</strong> (3.75 hours) per week on video editing. </p>
<p><strong>New Way</strong> - 45 minutes of recording (for one video) + 1 hour for editing and publishing = <strong>105 minutes</strong> </p>
<p>That's over a 45% decrease in the amount of time that it takes.</p>
<p>That time can be used to make other videos craft ideas or (hopefully) exercise and relax.</p>
<h2>Less Now = More Focus</h2>
<p>The things that I have done do not reduce the quality of any of the content that I'm creating. In fact, I believe that they strengthen the many things that we are doing and allow us to add more focus to the things that require it.</p>
<p>This will allow me to work on more things that will help PIT grow into a self-sustaining product that goes in line with what seems to be the logical path for it.</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/590181ba791e4bdf2a7a4e36" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/58ed3f0d791e4b02fc28e011</id>
  <title>BusyCal - A Powerful option on iOS</title>
  <updated>2017-04-11T20:39:31Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Johan Gustaphzon</name>
<email>gustaphzon@gmx.com</email>
<uri>http://appleyra.se</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p><img alt="*BusyCal* feature image" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/BusyCal-feature.jpeg" /></p>
<h2>Introduction</h2>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> is a calendar app for macOS and iOS that's developed by BusyMac. I was looking for an app that could show both my calendar and todos simultaneously. I have tried a few apps before with this functionality, but they all had some form of limitation. With this in mind I decided to give <em>BusyCal</em> for iOS a shot.</p>
<h2>Calendar</h2>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> is a really powerful app with many features. It supports different views and provides of information like your task list, the weather and moon phases.</p>
<h3>Month view</h3>
<p>By pinching and zooming with two fingers you can view 2 to 8 weeks in the month view. If you tap on a specific day it expands and show you all events of that day in a list. To make room for this it pushes next coming week down. This is my favourite function in all calendar apps I ever tried.</p>
<p><img alt="month view" src="https://www.busymac.com/images/bcl3ios-month-with-accordion@2x.png" /></p>
<h3>Week view</h3>
<p>The week view can show 2-7 days with the same technique as month view. Week view works both in portrait and landscape, which is quite unusual.</p>
<p><img alt="week view" src="https://www.busymac.com/images/bcl3ios-week-iphone-portrait-2d@2x.png" /></p>
<h3>List and day view</h3>
<p>The other two views is list and day view. List view shows all your events in a running list with a divider between days. Even though I like the month view, the day view is my most used. Here it shows your events in blocks with a timeline on the side. There is a divider at the top for all-day events. It's possible to move this divider depending on how many events you want to fit. Zoom the timeline by pinching with two fingers.</p>
<p><img alt="list view" src="https://www.busymac.com/images/bcl3ios-list-view@2x.png" /></p>
<h2>Todos</h2>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> is using Apple reminders to handle and sync todos. They show up in the calendar on their due date and time. If it only has a due date I show up with all-day events at the top. If you don't finish a task it automatically moves to the next day and shows as a all-day task.</p>
<p>There is an tap to manage and edit task, this is also the only place you can view undated tasks. They are showed as a list and you can sort by due date, list, tag, priority, title or manually.</p>
<p><img alt="todos" src="https://www.busymac.com/images/bcl3ios-to-dos-in-calendar@2x.png" /></p>
<h2>Other features</h2>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> supports iCloud, Google, Office 365 and Exchange. You can also use other CalDav servers such as Fruux, Kerio and Zimba.</p>
<p>You can apply tags to both tasks and events, one event or task can have multiple tags. This makes it easier to search and categories with filters. When searching you can do this by title, location, notes and tags. The result is showing a list.</p>
<p><img alt="tagging" src="https://www.busymac.com/images/bcl3ios-event-details-tags@2x.png" /></p>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> support natural language for creating events and tasks.</p>
<p><img alt="Other features" src="https://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/image.jpg" /></p>
<h2>Drawbacks</h2>
<p>In <em>BusyCal</em>, You are limited in options when creating repeating events. The app supports and can show different repeat options, but the need to be set in <em>BusyCal</em> for mac or an other app.</p>
<p>All tasks shows a one hour events in the calendar and therefore takes unnecessary much space. I would like a setting for choosing a shorter time.</p>
<p>Tasks that are automatically move to the next day lacks and indication that they are overdue. I would also like better handling for lists and tasks.</p>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> is an universal app that works on both iPad and iPhone. Unfortunately it doesn't use the bigger space on the iPad and looks more like a blown up iPhone app. I tested it on my iPad Air 2 and got a lot of unused space.</p>
<p><img alt="List view on iPad Air 2" src="http://a5.mzstatic.com/us/r30/Purple71/v4/60/ff/4f/60ff4fe7-00d7-7c70-3de0-9958c0d6b39e/sc1024x768.jpeg" /></p>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> doesn't sync settings between devices and lack a widget.</p>
<p>I get the feeling that this is an companion app for the Mac version. I would rather see a complete iOS version with a higher price.</p>
<h2>My Verdict</h2>
<p><em>BusyCal</em> is one of the best calendar apps I used but it has some flaws that keeps me from using it as my primary app for calendar. The month view is outstanding and the option to expand days is genius. But the way it puts events and tasks makes the day and week view cluttered. I would like a better overlap of events like Apple Calendar and a clear view of overdue tasks. I want more features to match the macOS version and better use of the bigger screen on iPad.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/se/app/*BusyCal*-calendar-reminders/id1035689743?mt=8&amp;amp;up=4&amp;amp;at=10lKZy&amp;amp;ct=pit"><em>BusyCal</em> - Calendar, Reminders &amp; To Dos - App Store</a> [$ 4.99]</strong></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/58ed3f0d791e4b02fc28e011" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/58e4fa23791e4b375b8da582</id>
  <title>Living in a Distraction Free Forest</title>
  <updated>2017-04-04T14:07:29Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>While I can't say for certain that I have <a href="http://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/adult-adhd/diagnosis-treatment/diagnosis/dxc-20198882">adult attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder</a>, I know, for the past several years, I have been both blessed and cursed with the ability to switch my mindset from one area to another very quickly. If my goals and ambitions were a wooden sculpture, this would be like me trying to carve a statue with a whittling knife.</p>
<p><img alt="sculpture photo by Len Williams" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/sculpture.jpeg" /></p>
<p>The biggest opponent to my daily productivity is the constant task switching that I do in my day to day. Focusing on one task at a time has really been a challenge. While working on something, the thought "I wonder what's happening on twitter" creeps in. Then while taking a "break", I remember that "thing" I need to accomplish. I then begin working on a different project.</p>
<p>Then the phone rings... "Hey can you take care of this user? Thanks!"</p>
<p>Now I'm three levels down into my task <a href="https://youtu.be/E1iqGiX0lSg">inception</a> and I left my totem at home. By the end of the day I've made several more jumps and lots of progress in many directions but just like my whittling metaphor, the cuts are numerous but all very shallow.</p>
<h2>The struggle is ongoing but I have a new tool to help with it</h2>
<p>In my yearly interview with <a href="http://productivityintech.com/pitpodcast/45">Francesco D'Allesio</a>, he mentioned the anti-distraction app <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/forest-stay-focused-be-present/id866450515?&amp;amp;">Forest</a>. This app, entices you to not look at your phone as an onscreen tree grows.</p>
<p><img alt="forest screenshot" src="http://i.imgur.com/JD9ZT7p.png" /></p>
<p>Every day, you are tasked to build a small forest. Each session is a tree. The look of the tree is determined by how long the session was. Shorter session will result in a bush, while longer sessions a tree of varying length. You will also receive an in-app currency that you can use to change the type of trees grown or (once you have accumulated enough currency) you can plant a real tree somewhere in the world (Hooray for feels!)</p>
<h3>Less Random Thoughts</h3>
<p>Remember when I mentioned that twitter and other social medias were a trigger for me to start working on something else? It's almost impossible to open Tweetbot without killing the tree that I'm currently growing. Of course there isn't anything from actually stopping me, but the reminder is enough to encourage me to show the discipline required to focus on the task at hand. This prevents the flood gates from opening.</p>
<h3>The Pomodoro Method</h3>
<p>Along with the remedy for distractions, Forest acts as a great <em>pomodoro</em> to do <em>focused work</em>.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://cirillocompany.de/pages/pomodoro-technique">pomodoro technique</a> is the process of working for set amounts of time (usually 25 minutes) and then taking scheduled breaks. There is often a set goal of pomodoros you would like to complete.</p>
<p>Forest allows you to track, not only your total time for the day and week but also how many sessions you were able to complete (and not complete).</p>
<p><img alt="" src="http://i.imgur.com/plNvppl.jpg" /></p>
<h3>Limitations of an iOS Anti-Distraction Tool</h3>
<p>Forest is a great iOS anti-distraction tool. The only problem is that it is, well,</p>
<p><strong>AN IOS TOOL...</strong></p>
<p>IOS has limitations that cannot be overcome. When you turn on forestit cannot do any kind of prevention. It can "punish" you with the death of your tree, but it can't switch you off of those bad tasks. This also does not prevent you from just distracting yourself with other devices (iPads, laptops, television).</p>
<p>Do not download this app (or any app) with the notion that this will create discipline in you. It won't. It can, however be used to help train your mind to focus on the task at hand and fight the urge to distract yourself with your phone.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>While forest hasn't become a secondhand thought to my workflow yet. It is very much a tool that I plan to use regularly until it does. It has also given me inspiration to look into other applications on different platforms to keep me focused on the task ahead.</p>
<p><a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/forest-stay-focused-be-present/id866450515?mt=8&amp;amp;uo=4&amp;amp;at=1001lqpL">Forest - iOS $1.99</a></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/58e4fa23791e4b375b8da582" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/58d5f038791e4b85985b7a35</id>
  <title>How 30 of Exercise or Less Really Does Help my Focus and Energy</title>
  <updated>2017-03-25T04:21:07Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>For the past couple weeks I've been trying my best to work out regularly. This has pushed me to try the 365 push-up challenge (1 push added for each day in the challenge. At the time of writing I'm on 23).  I have also started running more and tracking my progress in <a href="http://www.nike.com/us/en_us/c/running/nike-run-club">Nike+ Run Club</a>.</p>
<p>My runs are always been less than 30 minutes. If I don't have enough time I will do a 15 minute circuit which includes a speed rope, 35lb overhead press, push-ups and crunches. I do each to failure (or mistake in the jump ropes case) and keep repeating the cycle until the timer runs out.</p>
<p>My goal is to give myself the energy to make it through the day fully alert.</p>
<p>Before I started working out I was about 230 pounds and I would feel terrible for the second half of the day and into the evening.</p>
<p>I feel like the short term changes have a potent effect on my mind.  I haven't lost any weight (blame diet on this primarily), but on days I work out, I feel amazing all day. I don't feel like taking a nap at lunch and I have an easier time focusing.</p>
<p><img alt="Runner" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/runner-1.jpeg" /></p>
<p>The problem is all the days I have skipped. Days that I don't work out I feel worse than before. It is apparent that my body likes the physical jolt of my morning routine and doesn't take lightly to cheating.</p>
<p>I set a task for myself in todoist to repeat every day. The way it happens, it is the first thing I see in the morning when I put on my watch.</p>
<p><img alt="workout task" src="http://snappyimages.nextwavesrl.netdna-cdn.com/img/c0615a1ad8e12f0a1d933bba36ea32bd.png" /></p>
<p>I have also enlisted in the help of the app <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/streaks/id963034692?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1001lqpL">streaks</a> to help track and gamify my progress.</p>
<p><img alt="streaks app" src="http://productivityintech.com/files/images/streaks.png" /></p>
<h2>Sleep</h2>
<p>My sleep schedule wasn't terrible. I was getting about 7 hours of sleep per day (11:30pm - 6:30am). In the morning I would wake up and get ready for work. When I wasn't working out, I would have to recharge the batteries with a quick lunch nap.</p>
<p>Working out on the morning now requires me to move my schedule back one hour.  I do find myself struggling to fall asleep but making time in the morning gives me more energy throughout the day as well.</p>
<h2>Changes in Focus</h2>
<p>The biggest change has been in the quality of my focus. Lately I've been wrestling with completing tasks. I believe this may be some underlying issue relating to my chronic task-acceptance issues (in short intake on too much work and then go crazy trying to complete it all).</p>
<p>While the working out hasn't resolved the deeply embedded issue of doing too much. It has slowed down the tendency to switch from one incomplete task to another. Now I'm able to work longer and more intently.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>The trials I have started have immediate but short term affects. My energy and focus levels are consistently better on days that I exercise. Of course the problem is the initial drive required to get up early and actually work out.</p>
<p>It's been less than a month and I need more consistency before I can call it a habit. I do hope to get to that point as I can only imagine how the long term benefits would great increase my focus, flow, and productivity.</p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/58d5f038791e4b85985b7a35" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/58457f72791e4bab7a08fa88</id>
  <title>Just Breathe with Breathing Space</title>
  <updated>2016-12-05T06:53:00Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Johan Gustaphzon</name>
<email>gustaphzon@gmx.com</email>
<uri>http://appleyra.se</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>If I could give one piece of advice, take breaks. I don't mean stop to check email or twitter. Take a REAL break. For a few moments, sit back, close your eyes, take a deep breath and just...</p>

<p>...
<em>Relax</em>
...</p>

<p>Taking shallow breaths can cause uneccessary stress and tension. <em>Controlled breathing</em> stabilizes the nervous system and strengthens the immune system.</p>

<p>Apple has acknowledged this and released in their new app <strong>Breathe</strong> as a part of <em>watchOS 3</em>. If you really want to change your breathing habits without the purchase of a new <em>Apple Watch</em>, I recommend you look at <em><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/se/app/breathing-space/id960173337?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=10lKZy&amp;ct=pit">Breathing Space</a></em> by MindApps. <em>Breathing Space</em> efficiently teaches controlled breathing and works to help you reach the perfect breathing pace of <a href="http://ritahayes.com/mindfulness-and-breathing-practices/">6 breaths per minute</a>.</p>

<p><img alt="Banner" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/breathing-space-banner.jpg" /></p>

<h2>Usage</h2>

<p>To get started, place your headset microphone under your nose and breathe at a normal pace for 30 seconds. The app uses this determines your current breathing pace and generates a personalized program. This program is step-by-step. The program contains is accompanied with both voice and text guidance and features nice animations and background music. The length of program by default is 1 minute but can be adjusted and saved. Breathing Space also connects to your Health data and will generate custom programs for different situations like <em>relaxing</em> and <em>balancing</em>.</p>

<p>To make it more fun, they've created different levels to reach. To finish the first level, you need to do three exercises for at least 5 minutes and have a assessed BPM of 30. All the levels are available through a <strong>FREE</strong> in-app purchase.  With every level, the number of exercises and minutes increase while the BPMs decrease. In total, there are 8 levels with the goal of 6 BPM.</p>

<p><img alt="Utseende på Breathing Space" src="http://www.appleyra.se/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/breathing-space-ui.jpg" /></p>

<h2>Concerns</h2>

<p>The only concern I found is that <em>Breathing Space</em> hasn't been updated since September 2015. Also, it is only available on the iPhone and has not been optimized for the Plus-size models.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Breathing Space makes learning about controlled breathing fun. With it, I have been able to control my breathing and I would recommend it for anyone feeling stressed who needs help to change their breathing pace.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/se/app/breathing-space/id960173337?mt=8&amp;uo=4&amp;at=10lKZy&amp;ct=pit">Breathing Space - App Store</a>[$ 0.99]</strong></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/58457f72791e4bab7a08fa88" />
</entry>
<entry>
  <id>https://productivityintech.com/blog/582a2f07791e4b3adfda7838</id>
  <title>Changes To Productivity In Tech On The Server Side And Why We Were Not Publishing</title>
  <updated>2016-11-14T21:39:19Z</updated>
  <author>
<name>Jay Miller</name>
<email>kjaymiller@gmail.com</email>
<uri>http://productivityintech.com</uri>
</author>
  <content type="xhtml">
  <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p><strong>WARNING! This post is somewhat techy</strong></p>

<p><strong>TLDR:</strong> I haven't been publishing episodes because I've been moving our site from one host to another in order to save money, have more control over content and easier management.</p>

<p>You may have noticed a lack of posts for the past couple weeks. I have been working hard to migrate the servers from Libsyn/AWS to Digital Ocean. While this has been somewhat challenging, I look forward to the benifits that the community will enjoy because of it.</p>

<h2>Cost</h2>

<p>Cost of operations is always a factor when making decisions like this. Here is a current breakdown of the regular monthly costs before this transition.</p>

<p><strong>BEFORE</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>$15 - Libsyn: <em>Productivity in Tech Podcast</em></li>
<li>$15 - Libsyn: <em>PIT:Reflections</em></li>
<li>$4-6 - AWS: WebServer</li>
<li>$10 - Buffer</li>
<li>$10 - Dropbox</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>TOTAL:</strong> $56.00/month
<em>Does not include annual plans that would increase the monthly rate to about $80/month in extraneous services</em></p>

<p>This switch will remove the need for Libsyn and AWS and only charge for Digital Ocean.</p>

<p><strong>AFTER</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><s>$15 - Libsyn: <em>Productivity in Tech Podcast</em></s></li>
<li><s>$15 - Libsyn: <em>PIT:Reflections</em></s></li>
<li><s>$4-6 - AWS: WebServer</s></li>
<li>$10 - Digital Ocean</li>
<li>$10 - Buffer</li>
<li>$10 - Dropbox
<strong>TOTAL:</strong> $30.00/month <em>savings</em>:$240/year.</li>
</ul>

<p>I'm also happy that the <a href="http://productivityintech.com/patreon">patreon subscribers</a> who support Productivity in Tech have pledged enough to cover the server costs in full and have started funding some of the other expenses. This means we can lower our funding goals and get more amazing content and products to you.</p>

<h2>Content Management</h2>

<p>When your information is spread across multiple services it is harder to maintain everything. This is why we decided to move our blog off of Medium and put it <a href="http://productivityintech.com/blog">on the website</a>. Thanks to <em>Digital Ocean's</em> <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/company/blog/block-storage-more-space-to-scale/">Volume Storage Plans</a>, the podcast files are now on the same server as the website. This makes the server a one-stop shop for all <em>Productivity in Tech</em> content.</p>

<p><img alt="Creating a One-Stop Shop" src="http://i.imgur.com/zQIOvOB.png" /></p>

<h2>Freedom of Usage</h2>

<p>I have not written this piece as a praise to Digital Ocean for a criticism of the other companies. I believe that the different services that I was using were all great in their own right and had many advantages to using them (which is why I originally did). This migration was out of several minor frustrations.</p>

<h3>Uploading Episodes and blog posts</h3>

<p>Wouldn't it be nice if the process for loading podcast episodes and blog posts. I have been building the upload systems from the ground up. This means that the system will be flexible and customizable. It will also be a smiliar process across the board.  </p>

<h3>RSS</h3>

<p>When I started doing PITReflections! They were hosted on the Productivity in Tech Podcast feed. As a courtesy to listeners who wanted just the weekly podcast episodes,  the shows were separated. Naturally, there were some that wanted a Master feed with the shows combined. I was told by the team at Libsyn that there was no way of doing this without creating a third show. With us managing our own feeds (and the content sources) we can create not only the three feeds we need but even more feeds (like the much requested patreon feed(coming soon))</p>

<h3>Scalabity</h3>

<p><strong>Simple Systems Scale Better</strong>. This is why one of my favorite applications <a href="http://trello.com">Trello</a> is so powerful. The Productivity in Tech system is now much simpler and will be much easier to manage as it scales. Also with <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-resize-your-droplets-on-digitalocean">Digital Ocean's Droplet Resizing system</a>, I can quickly adjust the file size to match the usage needs.</p>

<p><hr />
<p>If you would like to know more about how the new system works, you can reach out to us on <a href="https://twitter.com/prodintech">twitter - @prodintech</a>.</p>
<p>Of course with any migration there may be a bug or two. Please let us know by sending us some <a href="http://productivityintech.com/feedback">feedback</a>!</p></p>
  </div>
</content>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://productivityintech.com/blog/582a2f07791e4b3adfda7838" />
</entry>
</feed>